<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Restart Until Special Room</name>
    <directory>restart_until_special_room</directory>
    <id>2917382429</id>
    <description>CTRL+R to keep restarting until treasure room is in the neighbor of starting room!
By default it seeks for treasure room, planetarium, and library.
You can change the list of special rooms to search in the menu.
Sightly press R to open config menu, again to close. UP and DOWN to move selection, LEFT or RIGHT to toggle.
With the menu, this mod may also be configured to seek for sacrifice room, cursed room, or shop too.
Enable the 'SkipCurses' option in menu to skip seeds with curse in stage 1 (e.g. curse of the blind).
The 'ItemQuality' option, which is a number, ensures the treasure room (or other special rooms) to spawn items with quality &gt;= that value.
Enable 'EntireFloor' to search the room in entire floor, not necessary to be neighbor of starting room, useful for searching planetariums.
Enable 'EdenStartItem' and set 'ItemQuality' to 4, to look for Eden seeds starting with quality 4 passive or active item.
If 'FindTreasureRoom' and 'EdenStartItem' is both on, it will stop restarting until one of Eden start item or treasure room item is quality 4.
Setting 'ItemId' option to look for a specific item. There is actually three options 'ItemIdHigh/Mid/Low' for digits of item ID you want to search.
In Greed Mode, only the 'ItemQuality', 'ItemId', and 'EdenStartItem' options is available.
Since you only want to visit the Shop in Greed Mode, pressing CTRL+R will restart and **directly teleport you into the shop** as a convinence. When 'ItemQuality' is specified (not zero), it will restart until the shop sell item(s) above that quality.

Hints:
CTRL+R only works in stage 1 to prevent accidental restarts.
You only need to press CTRL+R once, no need keep holding it for long.
When all special rooms are OFF in the menu, CTRL+R is simply a quick shortcut to holding R.
CTRL+R won't consume Eden Tokens when playing as Eden, which is actually good.
If you are annoyed waiting too long for special rooms, hold R to stop searching.
For controller users, press left-stick and right-stick at the same time instead of CTRL+R to reroll seed, press right-stick instead of R to open menu.
Difference with [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2560433301]Treasure Room Start[/url]: This mod is not only able to find treasure room in neighbor, but also ensure item quality in that!
Works in challanges (with treasure room) too.
    

Changelog:
v1.11 - Fixed: holding R now reliably cancels the restart loop (release R once after CTRL+R, then hold R to stop).

TODO list:
Restart until stage 13 (Home) spawns Mom's Knife?
Restart until Eden holds a specific passive / active item (DONE!)
What's your idea? Let me know in the comments below!
</description>
    <version>1.11</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Rooms"/>
    <tag id="Floors"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
